把斧头放下! 快点放下
Drop the ax!Drop the ax,man.
快住手!
Don't do this!
把斧头放下!
Drop the ax now!
不许动! 别再往前走! 你听到没有?
Freeze!Do not take another step!Do you hear me?
趴到地上!
Get down on the ground!
快点!
Do it!
放下斧头!
Drop the ax,man!
警员在他衣服口袋里找到的钥匙 就是这家酒店的
Uniform found the key in his pocket.Belongs to this hotel.
- 他有说什么吗?   - 没有
- He making any statements?   - No.
他就是从这里拿的斧头 完全疯了
That's where he got the ax.He was completely out of his mind.
他们把他装进运尸袋才带回了警局
They had to transport him back to the precinct in a body bag.
不! 不!
No! No!
让我出去!
Let me out!
住手!
Stop!
- 他身上没有任何伤口?   - 没有
- No cuts or wounds?   - None.
他身上肯定是别人的血迹
He was definitely wearing somebody else's blood.
这里到底发生了什么?
What the hell happened in here?
犯罪现场调查 纽约篇 第六季 第16集 Uncertainty Rules
CSI:ny Season6 Episode 16
小丑?!
Clowns?!
你和小丑一起去的?
That's what you're going with-- clowns?
这就是你的正式说法?
That's your official story?
他们想杀我
They were trying to kill me.
你是说 他们是那种 "兼职作杀人犯"的小丑
Oh,so they're the "homicidal on the inside" kind of clowns.
你先等等 让我先发全境通缉令 找两2个粉红卷发 大红鼻子的人!
Well,hang on a second,while I put out an APB for two guys with frizzy pink hair and big red noses!
他们把枪塞进我嘴里
They stuck a gun in my mouth.
张开嘴
Open your mouth.
快点!
Do it!
张开嘴!
Open your mouth!
张嘴!
Open it!
这支枪?
This gun?
这支枪吗 James? 这是一支装满了龙舌兰酒的水枪
This gun,James?This is a water gun filled with tequila.
- 这你又有何解释?   - 我不知道...
- Now what do you have to say about that?   - I don't know...
你不知道
You don't know.
之后的事情我都不记得了
That's the last thing that I remember.
James 你嗑什么药了? 吃了什么药?
What drugs are you on,James?What'd you take?
我没有嗑药
I didn't take anything.
好了 够了 你说谎也该说够了吧!
All right,enough,enough with the lying.Enough!
我们手上有你的驾照 James
We have your driver's license,James.
我们知道你在酒店和朋友们 一起庆祝21岁生日
We know that you were up there celebrating your 21st birthday with your friends.
事情变得不可收拾 然后呢?
Things got out of control,and so what happened?
我想起来了... 我只记得...
I remember... I remember...
我在水下
I was underwater.
和海马一起游泳...
Swimming with seahorses...
还有...还有...海星
and... a-and... starfish.
Mark 你去问Mark
Mark.Ask Mark.
Mark死了
Mark's dead.
他们都死了 James
They're all dead,James.
你把他们都砍死了
You hacked your friends to death.
快点说说你的动机
Now tell me why.
我觉得很冷
I'm cold.
这里真得很冷
It's really cold in here.
我想要...我想要回家
I wanna... I wanna go home.
我能回家了吗?
Can I go home now?
他肯定嗑药了
He's clearly on something.
瞳孔放大 出汗 发冷
Dilated pupils,cold sweats,tremors.
很可能是LSD(麦角二乙酰胺) 或其他精神类药物
Most likely LSD or some other psychotropic drug.
这就是他对车挥斧头 对警员命令置之不理的原因
Explains why he was  swinging  the ax at cars and didn't respond  to the officers on the street.
他那会正活在幻觉里
He was hallucinating.
放下斧头!
Drop the ax!
根据剂量的不同 影响可能持续 6到12小时
Depending on the dose,the effects could last anywhere between six and 12 hours.
期间会有短暂清醒 但可能会在 幻觉和清醒间多次反复
He has moments of lucidity,but he could go in and out of hallucinations during that time.
来看看
Let's see.
他是切尔西大学物理专业的 还是曼哈顿物理俱乐部会员
He's a physics major at Chelsea University and a member of the Manhattan Physics Club.
- 不应该是混混啊   - 很奇怪
- Kid's no dummy.   - Strange.
这样的孩子 没犯罪记录 干净得像张白纸
A kid like this,no record,clean as a whistle.
James的手机?
James's phone?
对
Yeah.
有Sara打过来的11个未接来电
Got 11 missed calls from a Sara.
女朋友?
Girlfriend?
还有一个他妈妈打来的
And one call from his mother.
James 是爸爸和妈妈 生日快乐! 希望你过得愉快
James,it's your dad and I.Happy birthday!I hope you're having fun.
生日快乐 孩子
Happy birthday,son.
别看书了 出去喝一杯
Put the books down.Go out and have a drink.
出去不醉不归
Got out and have ten drinks.
别教坏他!
Don't tell him that!
亲爱的 别喝太多了
Don't have ten drinks,sweetheart.
我们周五回家 爱你
We'll be home Friday.We love you so much.
帮我们跟Sara问好
And say hello to Sara for us.
生日快乐 儿子
Happy birthday,son.
生日快乐 James
Happy birthday,James.
怎么样?
What's up?
她是第一个
She was first.
伤口的角度说明斧子从高处砍下
Angle of the wound suggests the ax came down from above.
但是天花板很干净
But it was clean.
就是说 如果别人先死 天花板上会溅有血迹
So if one of the others were first,there would be a castoff pattern on the ceiling.
但说不好第二个是谁
It's hard to say who was next.
这个人的手 在另一个人的腿上
Well,this guy's hand... is on top of the other guy's leg.
他先倒下 James从背后砍了很多下
So,he goes down,James hits him in the back multiple times,
血喷溅到了墙上 还有卫生间门上
causing this blood spatter on the wall and the bathroom door.
然后是这个人 手臂在上面
And this guy gets hit; his arm falls on top.
好了 那这就是第二和第三个
All right,so,two,three.
猜测而已 说不好她可能是第二个
Maybe.There's nothing to rule out her as number two.
- 没错   - 那就是 第三和第四了
- Right.   - So,three,four.
水平的伤口
Horizontal wound.
斧子从后方直直砍过来
The ax came straight back.
没错 然后导致了墙上的血迹
Right,and boom,causing that castoff pattern on the wall.
血迹中间有一片空白
There's a break in the pattern-- a void.
那么她被杀前是谁站在这里?
So who was standing here when she was killed?
任何一个死者的衣服上 都没有溅上血迹
There's no castoff pattern on the shirts of any of our vics.
肯定另有其人
Someone else was right here.
这太疯狂了!
This is crazy!
James这辈子从没有嗑过药
James never did a drug in his life.
我们叫你过来就是想了解情况 Sara
Well,that's why we asked you to come down here,Sara.
也许你知道什么关键线索?
Maybe fill in some of the blanks?
这根本说不通
None of this makes any sense.
Mark Turner和Daniel Vaughn 是其中两个死者 你认识他们吗?
Two of the victims were Mark Turner and Daniel Vaughn.You know them?
认识 是他最好的朋友
Yes,they're his best friends.
那她们呢?
How about them?
你认识这两个女孩吗?
Do you know who these girls are?
不认识?
No.?
她们和你还有James不是同学
They didn't go to school with you and James
应该不是
I don't think so.
你知道James昨晚出去玩了吗?
Did you know James was going out last night?
知道
Yeah.
Mark和Daniel筹备的
Mark and Daniel set it up.
那是他21岁生日 你没打算去吗?
It was his 21st birthday.You weren't supposed to be with him?
James从来不在乎生日
James never made a big deal out of his birthday.
去年 他是在图书馆过的
Last year,he spent it in a library.
他说他算是...和爱因斯坦一起庆祝了
Said he was... celebrating with Einstein.
- James是个科学怪人?   - 对
- James is a science buff,huh?   - Yeah.
我能理解
I can relate.
我本来想给他办个派对的
I was gonna throw a party for him.
但是他让我保证不会
He made me promise not to.
Mark和Daniel说他们才不理他的拒绝呢
Mark and Daniel said they weren't taking no for an answer.
James...他不是那种爱玩闹的男生
James... he isn't a party guy.
他...他是那种派对上的"墙花"?
He... He's kind of a wallflower,you know?
就坐着看大家玩得开心就好了
He just sits back and watches everyone else have fun.
不过我不在乎
I don't care,though.
我爱他就是因为他不是那种 加入兄弟会的男生 你明白吗?
I-I love that he's not one of those fraternity-type guys,you know?
不 不 放开我!
No. No,get away from me!
- 放开我!   - 等一下 冷静一点
- Get away!   - Wait. Calm down.
他会怎么样?
What's gonna happen to him?
我也不知道 Sara
I wish I had a good answer for that,Sara.
那么说他说的是事实
So he was telling the truth.
他被两个小丑绑架了
He was kidnapped by two clowns.
在每个面具里各找到一根头发 属于两个男死者
Found a hair in each of the masks,and they came back  to the two male vics.
小丑就是他的朋友
The clowns were his buddies.
开什么玩笑?
Are you serious?
这一点都不好玩 伙计们
Not funny,guys.
生日快乐 伙计
Happy birthday,man.
生日快乐 兄弟
Happy birthday,bro.
我以为那是他的幻觉
I thought he was hallucinating.
那之后发生了什么呢?
So what happened after the jig was up?
不知道 要说猜谜水平 我们差不多
I don't know.Your guess is as good as mine,brother.
嘿 医生
Hey,Doc.
Sid取了死者指纹 查到了女死者身份
So Sid printed the vics.Got an I.D. on our two girls.
分别是Jackie Wright和Lacey Deshane
Names are Jackie Wright and Lacey Deshane.
之前都有非法持有毒品的前科
Both have priors for drug possession.
她们和嫌疑人是同学?
They go to school with our suspect?
不是 我看她们不像是上学的料
Nah,I don't think they seem like the school type.
她们更像是出入曼哈顿拘留所的类型
The only detention they've seen is probably Manhattan's House of Detention.
毒物检测也证实两个男性死者 服用的就是LSD
Tox also confirmed LSD in our two male vics.
但是女死者不是
But not the girls.
看来他们派对开得够奔放的
So they were partying pretty hard.
我听过很多派对玩出火的 但这孩子也玩得太过了吧
I've heard of people having a bad trip,but something set this kid off.
是的 或者过火的是他的同伙
Yeah. Or his accomplice.
你能想到是什么造成 墙上血迹中的空白吗?
You have any theories on who created the void in the wall?
不知道 我把血样送去化验DNA了
Nothing.I sent blood swatches to DNA.
Mark上衣上有不明污迹 还有...
Unknown stain on Mark's shirt,and...
James的牛仔裤上有不少的洗发水
trace amounts of shampoo on James' jeans.
洗发水
Shampoo.
现在就等药效过去 他交代谁是同伙了
Now,this guy needs to come down off the LSD and give up the other person in the room.
这个也许有所帮助
This might tell us.
这是James的上衣--警员在酒店 楼梯间发现的
This is James' shirt-- unis found it on the stairwell at the hotel.
不错啊
Nice.
看到了吗? 这里没有同样模式的血迹
You see?No corresponding castoff patterns across here.
对 那么不是他造成的那片空白
Yeah,so he didn't  create the void.
那就说明James是拿斧头的人
It would confirm that James was holding the ax.
没错 但在他上衣和牛仔裤上 都看不到中速喷溅的血迹
Yeah,but I don't see any medium-velocity blood spatter-- not on his shirt or  his jeans.
这些可是近距离的砍伤
And these are close-contact ax wounds.
如果James就是凶手 身上应该有相应的血迹
If James were the killer,there would be some  blood spatter evidence on him.
那么造成血迹空白的不是他 砍人的也不是他
So he didn't create the void,and he wasn't swinging that ax.
那他的朋友被屠杀时 他在那里做什么?
What the hell was he doing when his friends were being massacred?
噢 你不会真做了吧
Oh,no,you didn't.
噢 我还真做了
Oh,yes,I did.
嘿 Adam
Hey,Adam.
你有什么进展?
How far have you got?
我根据现场照片和DNA结果 有了初步的事件模拟
Uh,well,I have a prelim sequence of events based on the crime scene photos and DNA results.
放一下
Run it.
好
Okay.
那么Jackie Wright是首位遇害者
Okay. So,we know Jackie Wright was our first vic.
受伤的角度 天花板上没有溅上的血迹
Angle of the wound and no castoff pattern on the ceiling.
还有...
Now...
Mark Turner不是想冲向凶手 就是想要跑到门边
Mark Turner either tried to bum-rush the killer or make a run for the door,
但他背部中了一斧 倒地 凶手又朝他砍了几斧
but he took a shot in the back,went down and the killer hit him a couple more times.
从浴室门上的血迹喷射情况来看
Causing the blood spatter on the bathroom door.
另一个人 Daniel Vaughn 很可能是想干预
Now,the other guy,Daniel Vaughn,probably tried to step in.
太不明智了 他胸口中了一下 倒在了Mark的身上
Not wise,because he takes a hit to the chest,goes down,landing on top of Mark.
你怎能肯定这些人是第二和第三死者?
How do you know for sure these guys are number two and three?
因为姑娘衬衫上的DNA结果出来了
'Cause the DNA results came back from the girl's shirt,
那上面有所有3个死者的血迹
and there was blood from all three of the other vics on her.
所以在她被砍前每个人的血迹 都已在斧上了
So everyone's blood was on the ax before she got hit.
听着 Danny 你到那里时 浴室门是这么微微开着的吗?
Listen,Danny,was the bathroom door slightly open like this when you got there?
是 任何东西都没人碰过
Yep.Nobody touched anything.
Adam 回到第二个死者
Adam,go back to the second victim.
重点标出浴室门
Highlight the door.
对了
Right.
看--门的边缘没有血迹
Look-- no blood is on the edge of the door.
按照这样的模式 血迹绝对会溅到门边 除非...
Now,with a pattern like that,blood would have definitely gotten on the edge,unless...
除非它是关着的
Unless it was closed.
的确
Exactly.
James说他记得和海马还有海星 一起游过泳
James said he remembered swimming with the seahorses and the starfish.
他的牛仔裤上也有洗发水的痕迹
And he had traces of shampoo on his jeans.
James不是凶手
James isn't our killer.
他在浴室里畅游呢
He was tripping in the bathroom.
我没杀我的朋友
I didn't kill my friends.
我知道你没有 James 我知道
I know you didn't,James.I know it.
我怎么了?
What's happening to me?
你服用了LSD
You took LSD.
不 不 不 我...
No.No.No.No.I...
听我说 James
Listen to me,James.
你体验了幻觉 高度焦虑 强烈的妄想
You're experiencing hallucinations,heightened anxiety,intense paranoia.
我不可能那么做的
I wouldn't have done that.
- 我...   - 你朋友也吸食了
I-I-I... Your friends took it,too.
那是你21岁生日
It was your 21st birthday.
你很可能做了一些以前从没干过的事
You were probably doing a lot of things you hadn't done before.
我来解开你的手铐 好吗?
I'm going to take your handcuffs off,okay?
放松 你信任我吗?
Just relax.You trust me?
我知道你是个科研人员
I understand you're a man of science.
- 学习物理   - 量子物理
- Studying physics.   - Quantum physics.
那是很难的东西
That's heavy stuff.
你女友告诉我你在写统一场论的论文 （统一场论: 要求用单一的数学语言 描述引力 电磁力 弱力和强力）
Your girlfriend told me you're writing a paper about the unified field theory.
你跟Sara谈过?
You talked to Sara?
她在哪儿? 我能见她吗?
Where is she?Can I see her?
也许要等一会儿
Maybe in a little bit.
我这种感觉还要持续多久?
How long am I going to feel like this?
我需要你的帮忙 James
I need your help,James.
我需要你努力集中精神
I need you to try to focus.
记起昨晚发生的一切
Remember everything from last night.
我不知道
I don't know.
只有些...片段
There's just... pieces.
每个片段 不管多短 都很重要
Every piece,no matter how little,is important.
那两个姑娘是谁?
Who are the two girls?
- 你记得她们吗?   - 不记得
- You remember them?   - No.
你回酒店后又去了哪里?
Where did you go after you got back to the hotel?
酒吧 夜总会?
A bar,a club?
不...不 我记得...
No... No.I remember...
走出浴室
walking out of the bathroom.
看到了他们
Seeing them.
不!
No!
我不知道出了什么事
I don't know what happened.
你为什么问我这些问题?
Why are you asking me these questions?
我想回家
I want to go home.
为什么我不能走...?
Why can't I just go...?
为什么我不能回家?
Why can't I just go home?
James 我知道你很害怕
James,I know you're scared.
但是我们会扛过去的
But we're going to get through this.
我们俩 好吗? 你和我
The two of us,okay?You and me.
你不必回答不想回答的问题
You don't have to answer anything you don't want to.
我们慢慢来
We'll just take it slow.
一起努力解决这件事
Try to figure this out together.
好了 2个男性死者 Mark和Daniel
Okay,the two male vics,Mark and Daniel,
带着James到Tribeca大酒店 过他的21岁生日
bring James to the Tribeca Grand Hotel for his 21st birthday.
而那里有酒有毒品
And there's drinking and drugs.
这本是个他们只能模糊记得的夜晚
This was going to be a night that they only vaguely remember.
至于2位女性死者 Jackie和Lacey 并不是他们的朋友
As far as the two female vics,Jackie and Lacey were not their friends.
酒店经理说她们并没有和他们 一起登记入住
And the hotel manager said that the girls did not check in with them.
所以这些家伙要么是昨晚遇到她们
So the guys either met them at some point that night
然后一起回酒店继续派对
and they all went back to the hotel to continue the party.
对 要么她们本身就是派对上...
Right,or they were the party.
雇来 嗯 吹灭寿星蜡烛的
Hired to,uh,blow out the birthday boy's candle.
好了 现场所有血迹都属于死者
Right,okay.All the blood at the scene belongs to our victims.
斧子上也是同样的情况
And the same goes for the blood on the ax.
现在 我们知道除了James外 另外一个人用过它
Now,we know that someone other than James used it.
Hawkes 试试激光显微分解
Hawkes,try laser micro-dissection.
看能否从表皮细胞上分离出 可能留在斧把手上的血迹
See if we can separate the blood from any skin cells that might have been left behind on the handle.
我们还知道些什么?
What else do we have?
我还在等James的小腿肚上 咬痕的DNA结果
I'm still waiting on DNA from the bite mark on James' calf.
你告诉我 他不记得这事了?
You tell me he doesn't remember that?
现在他什么都不记得了
He doesn't remember anything at the moment.
所以我们得利用手上所有证据 拼凑起他昨晚的行动
So we're going to have to piece together his night with whatever evidence we have.
好吧 这是我的发现
All right,well,here's what I got.
Mark和Daniel是在傍晚6点登记的
Mark and Daniel checked into the hotel at 6:00 p.m.
我猜他们离开酒店 接到James 大约7:30回到酒店
I'm guessing they left,got James,got back to the room somewhere around 7:30.
在7:40叫了客房服务
They ordered room service at 7:40.
ATM记录显示8点他们都在酒店旁取款
ATM records show withdrawals from all of them at the bank right next to the hotel at 8:00.
那之后 没有信用卡或借记卡的交易记录
After that,no credit or debit card transactions.
所以他们不管去了哪里 都是付现金
So wherever they went,they paid cash.
而且他们都没用过手机
And none of them made any calls from their cell phones.
我们没法修复任何短消息 凶手砸碎了他们的手机
We couldn't retrieve any text messages because whoever we're looking  for crushed their phones.
但我挽救了一张他们的照片
But I was able to salvage a photo taken of one of them.
是昨晚8:45拍的
This was taken at 8:45 last night.
这些家伙知道如何联谊还是怎么的?
These guys know how to party or what?
我是说 他们组织的是老太太聚会吗?
I mean,what,they organize a Golden Girls  reunion?
受害者中有她们的亲戚吗?
Are any of our vics related to one of them?
- 没有 我查过的   - 哪里查的?
- No,I checked.   - Checked where?
Wesleyshire屋
Wesleyshire House.
那是个协助生活机构
It's an assisted living facility.
受害者里在那儿都没有亲戚
And none of the vics had any relatives there.
好吧 那他们在那里干什么?
All right,so what were they doing there?
下一个数字是O-71
And the next number is O-71.
我见过的最可爱男孩
Sweetest boys you'll ever meet.
恕我不敢苟同
I beg to differ.
Helen在亲那个男孩的脸颊时 差点踢到了水桶
Helen nearly kicked the bucket when she kissed that boy on the cheek.
你说他们来这里玩宾果游戏?
So you're saying that they came here to play bingo?
嗯 这个孩子--我想他叫Mark--
Well,this one-- I think his name was Mark--
说他们在为一部关于 疗养院的纪录片做调查
said they were doing research for a documentary about nursing homes.
- 我想他们来这儿不是为了 呃...   - 我可不蠢 小子
- Yeah,I don't think they were here to do,uh...   - I'm not stupid,sonny.
来这儿的年轻人并不多 我们为什么不找些乐子呢?
We don't get many youngsters visiting around here,so why not have some fun,right?
你要输了 Mary
You're going down,Mary.
我就要连起来了
I'm coming to get ya.
连起来看看 帅哥
Bring it on,hot shot.
我有说过我连续三年是州冠军吗?
Did I mention I was state champion three years running?
恕我不敢苟同
I beg to differ.
G-55
G-55.
宾果!
Bingo!
我说啥了 姐们?
What I tell ya,sister?
你赢不了这些技巧的
You don't mess with these skills.
宾果
Bingo.
他赢了
Bingo has been called.
他赢了多少?
How much did he win?
2万5千块
$25,000.
- 下一个数字式B-3   - 什么...?
- And the next number is B-3.- What...?
2万5千块?
25 grand?
这不是你祖母玩的那种宾果游戏
This ain't your grandmother's bingo game.
我们玩的赌注很高
We play high stakes.
增添趣味
Spices things up.
- 他把钱拿走了?   - 我们坚持的
- And he kept the money?   - We insisted.
恕我不敢苟同
I beg to differ.
他们赢得光明正大
They won it fair and square.
所以 是的 我坚持的
So,yes,I insisted.
显然 我们在酒店房间里没找到那笔钱
Well,obviously,we didn't find that kind of money at the hotel room.
没有 那可能就是动机
No.That could be our motive.
就这样了 先生们?
Is that all,gentlemen?
我可以想到比和你俩在这儿 干坐一整天更好的事去做
'Cause I can think of better things to do than sit here all day with you two.
恕我不敢苟同
I beg to differ.
嘿 Stell
Hey,Stell.
刚刚完成了斧子的激光显微分解 我找到了些上皮组织
Just completed laser micro-dissection on the ax,and I found some epithelials.
那要花点时间 但如果我们走运
Now,it'll take a little while,but if we're lucky,
他们属于除James的另外一个人
they belong to someone other than James.
好 我刚刚找到了拼图中的一片
Okay,well,I just got another piece of the puzzle.
James小腿肚上的咬痕有DNA结果了
DNA came back from the bite mark on James' calf.
我们系统中的某个人?
Someone in the system?
Calvin Moore
Calvin Moore.
有袭击罪和拒捕罪的前科
Priors for assault and resisting arrest.
显然 当2个警察因为他在公共场合喝酒 想逮捕他时 他从背后推了他们
Apparently,he put two officers on their back when they tried to arrest him for drinking in public.
等一下 这个正确吗?
Wait a second.Is this right?
说他3英尺9英寸(约合1.19米)
Says he's three-foot,nine.
他撂倒了2个警察?
He took down two officers?
还咬了其中的一个
And bit one of them.
我们上哪里可以找到他?
Do we know where to find this guy?
假释官给了我们工作地址
The probation officer gave us a work address.
Danny和Flack正赶过去
Danny and Flack are headed over there now.
耶!
Yeah!
我会在你可怜无生气的身旁跳跳舞
I'm gonna do a little dance around your pathetic,lifeless body.
我的经纪人会在台下扔一把折叠椅
My manager's gonna shove a folding chair under the ropes.
裁判会想要阻止我
The ref's gonna try to stop me.
嘣! 我用椅子砸中裁判 然后是你
Boom!I hit the referee with the chair,and then you.
血 血 血...现在裁判会及时赶到 看到我制服了你
Blood,blood,blood... Now the ref is gonna come through just in time to see me pin you.
观众们会疯狂的
The crowd goes wild.
你们是谁啊?
Who the hell are you?
不 不 不
No,no,no,no,no.
你们不能因为这个抓我
You're not locking me up for this.
是他们要求的
They asked for it.
好吧 我有点得意忘形 事情做得有点过火
All right,so I get a little carried away,take things too far.
谁和你一起的?
Who was with you?
没有人 只有我
No one.It was just me.
那里还有其他人
There was someone else in there.
我一个人干的
I only work solo.
- 为什么这么做?   - 你觉得呢?
- Why'd you do it?   - Why do you think?
为了钱
For the money.
- 真是废话   - 拿了多少钱?
- You bet your ass money.   - How much money you get?
- 1千块   - 1千块?
- A grand.   - A grand?
就为了1千块?
You did this for a grand?
没错 最容易的一次
Yeah.It was the easiest money I ever made.
- 你在扯什么?   - 你在扯什么?
- What are you talking about?   - What are you talking about?
看来你承认了昨晚犯的4起凶杀
We're talking about a quadruple homicide that apparently you committed last night.
- 我承认了?   - 没错 听起来就是
- That I committed?   - Yeah.That's what it sounds like.
昨晚?
Last night?
在受害人腿上发现了你的DNA
And we got your DNA on one of our vic's legs to prove it.
这些家伙死了?
These guys are dead?
我可没杀人
Hey,I didn't kill no one.
这两个小鬼昨晚进来
These two jokers  came in last night,
给我1千块 让我陪他们生日的哥们好好玩玩
gave me $1,000 to bring  their buddy,the birthday guy,into the ring.
我们就好好玩了玩
We put on one hell of a show.
1 2 3
One,two,three!
他们开心我也开心 然后他们就走了
They had fun,I had fun,and they left.
走时还活着
Alive.
行 那他们是不是很兴奋?
Okay,uh,were they,uh... were they high?
嗑药?
On drugs?
不觉得
No,I don't think so.
那这两个姑娘呢? 跟他们在一起吗?
What about these two girls?Were they with them?
没 就他们三个
No. It was just the three of them.
好了
All right.
去战斗吧
Go fight.
很好 补上了一块拼图 但这两姑娘是从哪冒出来的?
All right,that's another piece,but where do the girls come in?
他们怎么拿到药的?
And where'd they get the drugs?
我想帮忙
I want to help.
真的
I really do.
但我没碰LSD
And I didn't take LSD.
你不相信 是吗?
You don't believe me,do you?
我相信你是忘记你嗑药了
Well,I believe you don't remember taking LSD.
你和我还蛮有共同点的
You and I probably have a lot in common.
从来就没有狂欢的欲望 不够洒脱
Never had a desire to be the life of the party,unable to just let go.
你哥们是想让你放松一把 感受下疯狂的世界
I think your buddies just wanted you to loosen up,take a moment to let the world happen to you.
确实够疯狂的
It definitely happened to me.
为什么我不记得了?
Why can't I remember?
放轻松 会记起来的
Just relax.It'll come in time.
如果不呢?
And what if it doesn't?
为什么不跟我聊聊你的研究?
Why don't you tell me about your,uh... your studies?
聊聊你写的论文
Tell me about that paper you're writing.
致爱因斯坦的公开信
"An Open Letter to Albert Einstein.
我得提醒你一下 爱因斯坦早死了
" I hate to break it to you,James,but Einstein's dead.
但他的理论还在
Not his ideas.
爱因斯坦相信宇宙万物都是可预测的
Einstein believed that everything in the universe is predictable.
直到Niels Bohr用量子论驳倒了他 （丹麦物理学家 他和其子都获得过诺贝尔物理学奖）
Until Niels Bohr proved him wrong at the atomic level.
原子核外的质子和电子运动是随机的
Protons,electrons flying around a nucleus in a completely random fashion.
爱因斯坦可没同意
Yeah,Einstein didn't buy it.
- 他说上帝...   - "难以相信上帝居然也掷骰子" (爱因斯坦原话)
- He said that God...   - "I can't believe God plays dice with the universe.
我常常想起这句话
" That phrase comes to mind often in my field.
生命中有时候 总会希望世间万物都是可测的
There have been times in my life where I wish everything was as predictable as you say,
但我相信你会发现这个世界的美好...
but I think you'll find the world's a far more interesting place...
James! James! James!
James!James! James!
你在做什么? 嗯?
What are you doin'?Huh?
James
James.James. James.
是我 我 Mac
It's me.It's me.It's Mac.
- 我骑了一头牛   - 什么?
- I rode a bull.   - You what?
一头牛
A bull.
告诉我 把你知道的全告诉我
You tell me.Tell me what you remember.
我骑了一头牛
I rode a bull.
它没有脸
It didn't have a face.
我记起来了
I remember.
好 一头牛
Okay. Okay. A bull.
城里只有两家
Well,there's only two in the city.
另一家在布鲁克林
The other one's in Brooklyn.
Danny跟那家的酒保聊过了 受害人没去过那里
Danny already spoke to the bartender out there,so,no... no,our vics weren't there.
好的 没问题
Yeah,will do.
生意怎样?
Okay.How's it going?
慢点... 让我猜猜
Wait... Let me guess.
来杯科斯莫 还是马蒂尼?
Cosmo or... an appletini.
我也猜猜
Let me guess.
来自长岛 可能是迪克斯山(纽约地名)
Long Island,maybe Dix Hills.
经理逼我们这么说
My manager makes us talk like that.
有事情问你
Got a question for you.
记得这些小伙吗?
Remember these guys?
记得 就昨晚
Yeah. From last night.
几个大款 一掷千金
They were,uh,big spenders,flashing a lot of cash.
他们... 他们玩得很开心
They were,uh... They were really funny.
玩得很疯
They got really wasted.
这个家伙还骑上了Pedro
This guy here actually took on Pedro.
谁是Pedro?
Who's Pedro?
骑到四级
Rode him to level four.
对城里娃而言 相当不赖
Pretty good for a city boy.
还记得他们什么时候进来的吗?
You remember about what time they came in?
大概12:15
Maybe 12:15.
有没有人嗑药?
Any of them seem high?
不觉得
I don't think so.
一起来的姑娘也没有嗑
Neither were the,uh,girls they were with.
姑娘?
What girls?
有2个姑娘...
There were these two girls.They,uh...
给所有人买了一轮酒
they ordered  a round of shots for everyone.
像是在3个小伙杯里放了点东西进去
Come to think of it,they might have put  a little something extra  in three of the shots.
他们是遇见姑娘前还是之后喝醉的?
So,were these guys pretty liquored up before they met the girls,or...?
他们不是在这里碰面的 一起进来的
They didn't meet the girls here.They all walked in together.
- 谢谢你配合   - 很荣幸 帅哥
- Thanks for your time.   - My pleasure... cowboy.
- Stell?   - 查到哪里了?
- Stell?   - Where are we?
他们在12点和12:15之间搭上了 那2个姑娘
They hooked up with the girls some time between 12:00 and 12:15 a.m.,
从摔跤场到酒吧就一段路
which is a small window,considering they had to take a cab from the wrestling thing up to the bar.
老实跟你说 没啥头绪了
But to be honest with you,I don't know where we are.
通知Danny 让他到第40街的 出租车库和我碰面
Get a hold of Danny.Have him meet me at the cab depot on 40th.
出租车库?
Cab depot?
记得死者衬衫上的污迹吗?
Remember the unknown trace on our vics' shirts?
那是防冻剂
It's antifreeze.
另外 Sid发现其中一个死者肩上 有安全带的擦伤
Plus,Sid told us  that one of the vics had a bruise on his shoulder from a seat belt.
我想他们遇到了车祸 而且程度不轻
I'm thinking they got into an accident,and it wasn't just a fender-bender.
我们在找一辆损伤严重的出租车
We're looking for a pretty banged-up cab.
发现什么告诉我
All right,let me know what you find.
很不寻常
Strangest thing.
如何见得?
Came out of nowhere.
街灯柱?
The lamppost?
- 无缘无故地撞上了街灯柱?   - 没错
- The lamppost came out of nowhere?   - Right.
冲上人行道时就很可能撞到
They have a tendency to do that when you're driving up on the sidewalk.
就是这么回事
This is what I'm saying.
Gordon先生 你没有报告车祸
Mr.Gordon,you never reported the car accident.
有什么理由吗?
Is there a reason for that?
我现在不就在说嘛
I'm reporting it to you now.
听着 你认识这些小伙吗?
Look,do you remember these guys?
昨晚你在Ludlow附近酒吧放下了他们
You dropped them off at a bar over on Ludlow last night.
貌似是这么回事
Something like that.
"Something like that.
认识她们不? 她们也在一起吗?
" You remember these girls?Were they with them?
我的耐心快用完了 Gerald
I'm losing my patience here,Gerald.
老实交代 否则以违规驾驶拘留你
Tell us what you know,or I'm gonna lock you up for reckless driving.
- 你不能这么做   - 试试看
- You-You can't do that.- Watch us.
我说不能 是因为当时不是我在开车
No,no,I mean,you can't because,uh,I wasn't the one driving.
别管了
Get outta here.
快走!
Just go!
他们塞给我100块车费和1500块赔偿金
They gave me a hundred bucks  to drive the cab and...  another $1,500 for the damage.
1600块就收买你了?
$1,600 to flush your medallion down the toilet?
就是这么回事
This is what I'm saying.
好家伙 Gerald
Good man,Gerald.
他车里装了摄像头
He's got security cameras in here.
难以想象我居然跟侏儒摔跤!
I can't believe I wrestled a midget!
小矮人!
Little person.God!
鬼才信我居然跟小矮人摔跤
I can't believe I wrestled a little person.
叫上这两个妞
Pick up these girls.
别 别
No,no.
别担心 Gerald 不管你的事
Relax,Gerald,you're off duty.
停在那里
Freeze it right there.
看看是否吻合
Let's see if they match.
那是Lacey Deshane
That's Lacey Deshane.
这是Jackie Wright
And that's Jackie Wright.
他们就随随便便搭上这两个姑娘?
So they just randomly picked up these girls last night?
看起来是
Looks that way.
真够背的 这辆车
Man,that's some bad luck.Of all the cabs.
美女去哪儿?
Where you headed?
就随你们
Wherever you guys are going.
- 进来吧   - 好的
- Get in.   - All right.
怎么样?
What's up?
- 要不我们去...   - 赶紧开车!
- What do you say we hit...   - Just drive!
这两个姑娘不知道去哪里
Okay.Those girls didn't know what they were in for.
但她们知道怎么给小伙们下LSD
Well,they knew enough to slip the guys some LSD.
估计是盯上了他们手里的钱
Most likely to get their hands on the cash.
倒回去停车的地方
Can you go back to where the cab first pulls over?
就这里
Right there.
Jackie把什么东西放进了包里
Jackie puts something in her purse.
放到最大
How close can you get?
看看
Let's see.
像是一把枪
That looks like a gun.
她们刚从这房子出来 肯定有鬼
They came from right here.Something happened up in that apartment.
好吧 我来说
Uh,all right,I'll start.
我和我搭档正在给纽约警署招人
Me and my partner here are recruiting on behalf of the NYPD.
找几个可靠的卧底
Looking for a couple of good guys to do some undercover work.
混进人堆里就找不到的那种
You know,inconspicuous types who blend in.
你看起来挺合适 有没有兴趣?
We think you got what it takes.You interested?
让他们进来
Let 'em in.
想要什么?
What you two want?
真对不住
Oh,I'm sorry.
招待不周
Where're my manners at?
不坐下再说?
Why don't you boys have a seat?
看起来像是枪伤
That looks like a gunshot wound.
伙计 你没事吧?
You all right there,chief?
小伤而已
It ain't nothin'.
这样才够爷儿们
Mama said there'd be days like this.
说说Jackie Wright和Lacey Deshane
Tell us about Jackie Wright and Lacey Deshane.
这两个婊子死了?
Ain't them bitches dead?
是啊 你都知道些什么?
Yeah,what do you know about that?
不比你多 我想是这样
Same as you,I suppose.
我的眼线在城里到处都是
I got eyes and ears all over this city.
有个疯子扮Paul Bunyan杀了那些姑娘 (北美传说中的伐木巨人)
Some crazy bastard went all Paul Bunyan on them girls.
那你就是他的蓝色斧头Babe了
So that makes you Babe the Blue Ox.
她们昨晚离开这套公寓的 我们清楚Jackie还带了枪
They left this building last night.We know that Jackie was carrying a gun.
那里是怎么回事?
Now why would that be?
我也不知道
I don't know.
也许是教女无方?
Bad parenting,maybe?
她应该清楚 不能玩枪的
She should know better than to play with guns.
没错 你还真是模范老爸
Yeah,you're quite the role model.
嗨 听清楚了 Sipowicz (美剧里的警探名)
Hey,check this out,Sipowicz.
我对她们的只有爱 懂没?
I had nothing but love for them girls.Huh?
我给她们钱 给她们填饱肚子
I put money in their pockets,food in their mouths.
现在发生的一切 真是奇耻大辱
So it's a crying shame what happened.
如果你们逮捕凶犯 我会非常高兴
When I heard you arrested someone,I was a happy man.
不过 现在 我在想...一切都变了
But see,now,I'm thinking... Things has changed.
那男孩是目击证人吗?
That boy a witness?
好了
All right.
我和你们谈完了
I'm done with you two.
现在你们可以滚出我家了
Now get your asses out of my house.
他的名字是 Rufus Knox
DANNY: His name's Rufus Knox.
毒贩 母亲是妓女
Drug dealer,twitchy son of a bitch.
他和那两姑娘什么关系?
What's his connection to the girls?
她们为他在地下夜总会售毒
They worked for him selling drugs in an underground nightclub.
Rufus也是她们前两次被捕的保释者
Rufus also bailed them out on their last two arrests.
这么说他们之间的关系闹僵了 姑娘们冲他脸上开了一枪 然后跑路
Okay,so the relationship goes south,the girls put a bullet in his face and then take off.
正好遇到James和他朋友开着的士路过
Right when James and his buddies drive by in the cab.
没有目击证人的话 这些都是间接证据
Without a witness,it's all circumstantial.
这可不是间接证据 激光显微切割法 确认了斧柄上的上皮细胞DNA...
Nothing circumstantial about this: Laser micro-dissection identified the epithelials  on the ax handle.
属于Rufus Knox 已让地检申请搜查令了
DNA belongs to Rufus Knox.Already called the DA for a warrant.
- 太棒了   - 嗯 我们行动吧
- Bingo.   - All right,let's move.
进去 进去 进去!
Move,move,move!
这里没有人
There's no one here.
只有我 我发誓
It's just me,I swear.
安全
We're all clear.
什么都没有
Nothing.
他在哪? 他去哪里了?!
Where is he? Where is he?!
趴下! 趴下!
Get down! Get down!
你认为我只是在胡闹 哈?
You think I'm pissing around here,huh?
你这SB小子!
You punk-ass kid!
连根头发都别想动!
Don't you move a hair on your head!
James!James!
别开枪 James 别开枪 孩子
Don't do it,James. Don't do it,son.
听好警察的话 孩子
Listen to the nice police officer,kid.
姑娘们...你们这些疯婊子
Girls... you some crazy-ass bitches.
你们想要离开 哈?
Yeah,you want out,huh?
你们想走 那就让你们心满意足!
Oh,well,you want out,well,you got it!
你就在那里
You were there.
你杀死了我的朋友们
You killed my friends.
把枪放下 James
Put the gun down,James.
你不想这么做的 相信我 孩子
You don't want to do this.Trust me,son.
我得告诉你们--这个结局很好
I'm gon' tell ya-- this gon' be good.
放下枪! 放下枪
Lower the gun! Lower the gun.
跪在地上 跪在地上!
On your knees. On your knees!
双手放在脑后 快点!
Hands behind your head.Do it!
转过身去 转身!
Turn around.Turn around!
她吓得魂都没了 但还是录了口供
She's scared out of her mind,but she's talking.
显然两个女性死者想退出毒品买卖
Apparently our two female vics wanted out of the drug business.
我只想重新开始 你明白吗?
I just want to start over,you know?
我有朋友住在加州-
I got a friend that lives out in Califor-
帮帮忙闭上你们的嘴巴!
Do yourself a favor just shut your mouth!
在我为你们做了这么多后
After all I done for you.
你们想离开
You just want out.
就想那样做
Just like that.
我开始感觉 我没受到应有的尊重
You know,I'm starting to get the distinct feeling here that I'm a little underappreciated.
Rufus手下的一个姑娘看到他们和James 及他的朋友们进了饭店
One of Rufus' girls  spotted them going into the hotel with James  and their friends.
James的朋友们是附带伤害
James' friends  were collateral damage.
是啊 本来他也会没命 幸亏他躲在浴室
Yeah.Well,he would've been,too,if he hadn't been in the bathroom.
Rufus 不会留下任何目击证人
Rufus wasn't leaving any witnesses.
这种时间上的巧合太难以置信了
The timing on this thing is unbelievable.
两姑娘冲出公寓时 刚好他们开车路过
Driving up in the cab just as the girls ran out of the apartment.
然后发生了后面的事 这种概率有多大?
The sequence of events,I mean,what are the odds?
无巧不成书
Worlds colliding.
感觉怎么样?
How you feeling?
内疚
Guilty.
就像...就像这一切都是我的错
Like... this is all my fault.
因为我的关系 我的好友都死了
My best friends are all dead because of me.
不是这样的 James
That's not true,James.
这就是生活 它总是不断给你意外
This is life.It throws things at you.
有些是福 有些是祸
Some good,some bad.
没人能预知未来 哪怕你是爱因斯坦
No one could have predicted what happened,not even if you're Albert Einstein.
那我现在该干什么?
So what do I do now?
你刚刚经受了一场重创
You've been through a major trauma.
它很难恢复的
It's gonna be tough.
所以别假装知道所有答案
So don't pretend to have all the answers.
去和别人谈谈
You talk to people.
如果你有什么感觉 就说出来
You're feeling something,you reach out.
依靠那些爱你的人们
Depend on the people who love you.
你会好起来的
You'll be all right.
嗨 妈妈 爸爸
Hey,Mom,hey,Dad.
- 宝贝...   - 上帝 我想你们
- Oh,baby...   - God,I missed you.
我真高兴 我们回家吧
Oh,I'm so dang happy.Let's go home.
犯罪现场调查 纽约篇 第六季 第16集 Uncertainty Rules
CSI:ny Season6 Episode 16 Uncertainty Rules